Portaldot is brand-new. When a transaction fails, the chain returns a raw code — no name, no message, no fix.
pdk decodes those codes. Fresh venv → pip install portaldot-pdk — v0.1.6 already on PyPI.
pdk doctor — endpoint, chain, runtime 1002, 31 pallets, ink! 3.x compat.
pdk accounts — pre-funded Alice / Bob / Charlie. Answers the most-asked Discord question: "how do I get POT?"
pdk pallets — all 31 pallets, straight from chain metadata.
pdk storage — read any chain value. Here: the current block number.
pdk keys //Alice — inspect or generate keypairs. SS58 format 42 — Portaldot's standard.
pdk simulate — preview fee + feasibility before sending. Built from the real fee oracle.
pdk send — a real on-chain transfer. 1 POT Alice → Bob. Gas paid in POT. No mocks.
pdk seed — fund extra dev accounts from a YAML fixture (Dave, Eve, Ferdie).
pdk debug --demo — the hero. Submits a real failing tx and decodes it: named error, plain English, numbered fix.
pdk explain --module 6 --error 2 — decodes the RAW module-and-error code. Nothing else in the Portaldot ecosystem does this.
pdk debug --fix — diagnose AND apply the fix. One command, end-to-end remediation.
pdk report — group recent failures by type. Triage at a glance.
pdk watch — stream chain events live. Filter by pallet.
pdk ai-setup — wizard for the optional AI layer.   ·   14 commands. Real POT gas. 1st place — Builder Tools.